<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mírian Bruckschen Motta Barros&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://mirianbr.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mírian Bruckschen Motta Barros&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mirianbr.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://mirianbr.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 15:48:31 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mirianbr.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello, I&amp;rsquo;m Mírian! 👋🏼
I&amp;rsquo;m an experienced IT professional, with a mixed industry, government and academy background, passionate about crafting solutions to help people and businesses thrive. I provide training and consulting services on technical documentation, customer service and business processes to support these areas.
My interests range from language and culture to education, law, politics and technology. I hold a Master degree in Computer Science from PUCRS, and three Bachelor degrees: Law (2020), Information Systems and Computer Science, all from Unisinos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://mirianbr.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 15:45:37 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mirianbr.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon. Stay tuned! 👀</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ludum Dare 49 and Interactive Fiction</title>
      <link>https://mirianbr.com/posts/2021-10-05-ludum_dare_and_interactive_fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mirianbr.com/posts/2021-10-05-ludum_dare_and_interactive_fiction/</guid>
      <description>This weekend I participated for the very first time in the Ludum Dare game jam, with my also first interactive fiction piece, and I have to say, I loved both experiences. OK, not so much the deadline pressure, but I had made a good schedule planning, and could follow it most of the time.
Until a few days ago, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about interactive fiction. My husband told me I would like it when I said I was looking for enrolling in Ludum Dare this time, maybe with something low code, to do some educational game or something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A pytesseract hello world in Portuguese under Anaconda</title>
      <link>https://mirianbr.com/posts/2021-07-13-pytesseract_hello_world_in_portuguese_under_anaconda/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mirianbr.com/posts/2021-07-13-pytesseract_hello_world_in_portuguese_under_anaconda/</guid>
      <description>Playing with OCR using python for the first time, I came across tesseract and its Python wrapper, pytesseract. I started by (and recommend) this detailed tutorial, that covers the tesseract and pytesseract installation, assuming you already have Anaconda.
Forcing the tessdata-dir to be found Depending on your installation, though, things may not work at first. Mine didn&amp;rsquo;t, for the tessdata-dir wasn&amp;rsquo;t being found (Error opening data file... error). In order to resolve this, I followed pytesseract usage hint to force the tessdata directory:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USD-BRL exchange rates in Google Sheets and Excel</title>
      <link>https://mirianbr.com/posts/2021-07-09-usd-brl-exchange-rates-in-google-sheets-and-excel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mirianbr.com/posts/2021-07-09-usd-brl-exchange-rates-in-google-sheets-and-excel/</guid>
      <description>Doing taxes can be a challenge. If you receive money in a foreign currency, being a Brazil resident, income tax it is definitively tricky.
If you receive money from abroad, you need to do some math each month to learn what is the amount you should consider when calculating your taxes. Regardless of the currency your money is in, you need to convert it first to US dollars, then to Brazilian Reais (BRL), and just then you can do your tax calculation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First title</title>
      <link>https://mirianbr.com/posts/2021-07-07-my-first-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mirianbr.com/posts/2021-07-07-my-first-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>First post!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
